there's more seats on this side
for people walking in late. So just to make sure you're in cs231n deep
learning neural network class for visual recognition. Anybody in the wrong
class?
Welcome, happy new year happy first day of
winter break. This class CS231n is the second offering
of this class We have literally doubled our enrolment from 180 people last
time
we offered to. About 350 of you signed up. Just a couple of words to make
us all legally
covered, we are video recording this class. So, you know, if you're
uncomfortable about this for today just go behind that camera or go to the
corner where the camera's not gonna turn but we are going to send out forms
for you to fill out in terms
of allowing video recording so that's just one bit of housekeeping so
Alright, so my name is Fei-Fei Li, I'm a professor at the computer science
department
So this class I'm co-teaching with two senior graduate students and one of
them
is here. He's Andrej Karpathy. Andrej can you just say hi to everybody we
have what I don't think Andrej needs too much
introduction all of probably know his work
follow his blog his Twitter follower
Andrej has way more followers than I do. He's very popular (laughter) And
also Justin Johnson who is still
travelling internationally but will be back in a few days so Andre and
Justin so
will be picking up the bulk of the lecture teaching Today I'll be giving
the first lecture but as you probably can see that I'm expecting the
new-born very soon
speaking of weeks so you'll see more of undrained Justin in lecture time we
will
also introduce a whole team of TAs towards the end of this lecture. Again
people who are looking for seats, if you go out of that door and come back,
there's
a whole bunch of seats on the side. So for this lecture we're going to
give the introduction of the class what kind of problems we work on and the
tools we'll be learning so again welcome to CS231n this is a vision
class it's based on a very specific modelling architecture called neural
network and even more specifically mostly on convolution neural network and
a lot
of you hear this term maybe through a popular press article or
coverage we tend to call this the deep learning network Vision is one of
the fastest growing field of
artificial intelligence. In fact CISCO has estimated and
(we are on day 4 of this) by 2016, which we already have arrived, more than
85% of
the internet cyberspace data is in the form of pixels
or what they call multimedia so we basically have entered an age of vision
of images and videos. And why is this so? while partly to a large extent
is because of the explosion of both the Internet as a carrier of data as
well as
sensors. we have more sensors that the number of people on Earth these days
every one of you is carrying some kind of smart phones, digital cameras and
you know cars around on the street with cameras so the sensors
have really enabled the explosion of visual data on the internet but visual
data or pixel data is also the hardest data to harness so if you have heard
my
previous talks and some other computer vision professors we call this
the dark matter of the Internet
why is this the dark matter just like the universe is consisted of 85% dark
matter dark energy is these matters that energy that is very hard to
observe
we can infer it by mathematical models in the universe, on the internet
these are the
matters pixel data are the data that we don't know we have a hard time
grasping the contents Here's one very very simple specs for you to consider
so today
YouTube servers for every 60 seconds will have more than 150 hours of
videos uploaded
onto YouTube servers for every 60 seconds
think about the amount of data there is no way that human eyes can sift
through
this massive amount of data and make annotations
labelling it and describe the contents Think from the
perspective of the YouTube team or Google company if they want to help us
to search, index, manage and of course for their purpose put
advertisement or whatever manipulate the content of the data were at a loss
because nobody can hand annotate this The only hope we can do this is
through vision
technology, to be able to label the objects find the things, find the
frames
you know locate where basketball video were Kobe Bryant's making like that
awesome shot and so these are the problems we are facing today that the
massive amount of data and the challenges of the dark matter so
computer vision as a field that touches upon many other fields of
studies so I am sure that even sitting here
many of you come from computer science but many of you come from biology
psychology
are specializing in natural language processing or graphics or robotics or
or you know medical imaging and so on so as a field computer vision is
really a
truly interdisciplinary field what the problems we work on the models we
use
touches engineering physics biology psychology computer science and
mathematics
so just a little bit of a more personal touch I am the director of the
computer vision
lab at Stanford in our lab, I work with graduate students and postdocs and
even
undergraduate students on the number of topics and most dear to our own
research
who some of them you know Andrej, Justin come from my lab
number of TAs come from my lab we work on machine learning which is part
a superset of deep learning we work a lot cognitive science and
neuroscience as well
as the intersection between an NLP and speech so that's the kind of
landscape of computer vision research that my lab works in. So also to put
things
in a little more perspective what other computer vision classes now we
offer
here at Stanford through the computer science department are clearly you're
in
this class CS231n so you some of you who have never taken computer vision
probably heard of computer vision for the first time probably should have
already
done cs131 that's a intro class of previous quarter we offer and then and
then next quarter which normally is offered this quarter but this year as a
little shifted there is an important graduate-level computer vision class
called cs231a offered by professor Silvio Savarese who works in robotic
3d vision and a lot of you ask us the question that do these replace each
other this class CS231n
vs CS231a and the answer is no. if you're interested in a broader
coverage of tools and topics of computer vision as well as some of the
fundamental topics that come that relate you to 3D vision, robotic vision
and visual recognition you should consider taking in 231a that is the
more general class 231n which we'll go into starting today more deeply
focuses
on a specific angle of both problem and model Model is neural network and
the
angle is visual recognition mostly but of course they have a little bit of
overlap but that's the major difference And next quarter we also have
possibly
a couple of advanced seminar level class but that's still in the
formation stage so you just have to check the syllabus so that's the kind
of computer
vision curricula we offer this year at Stanford. Any question so far? yes
Is CS131 a strict requirement for this class? CS131 is not a strict
requirement for this class but you'll soon see that if you've
never heard of computer vision for the first time I suggest you find a way
to
catch up because this class has assumes a basic level of understanding of
computer vision you can browse the notes and so on.
A rest of today is that I will give a very brief broad stroke history of
computer vision
and then we'll talk about 231 and a little bit in terms of the organization
of the class I actually really care about sharing with you this brief
history of computer
vision because you know you might be here primarily because of your
interest
in this really interesting tool called deep learning and this is the
purpose of this class
We are offering you an in-depth look and then
and just journey through what this deep learning model is but without
understanding the problem domain without thinking deeply about what this
problem is
it's very hard for you to go on to be an inventor of the next model that
really solve the big problem in vision or to be you know developing,
making impactful work in solving a hard problem and also in general problem
domain and model the modeling tools themselves are never never fully
decoupled
They inform each other and you'll see through the history of deep learning
a little
bit that the convolutional neural network architecture come from the need
to solve
a vision problem
And then, vision problem helps the deep learning algorithm to evolve and
back and forth so is really important to you know I want you to finish this
course and
feel proud that you're student of computer vision and of deep learning so
you
have this both the toolset and the in-depth understanding of how to use the
toolset to tackle important problems so it's a brief history but
doesn't mean it's short history so we're gonna go all the way back to
540 million years ago so why did I picked this you know on the scale
of Earth history this is a fairly specific range of years while so I don't
know if you have heard of this but this is a very very curious period of
the
Earth's history biologists call this the big bang of evolution Before
540 million years ago
the Earth is a very peaceful of its pretty big pond of water so we have
very simple organisms
these are like animals that just floats in the water and the way they eat
and hang out on
a daily basis is you know they float and if some kind of food comes by near
their mouth or whatever they just open their mouths grabbed it and we don't
have too many different types of animals. But something really strange
happened around 540
million years suddenly from the fossils we study there's a huge explosion
of species
biologist call speciation like suddenly for some reason something hit the
earth that animal
start to diversify and they got really complex they really start to have
predators and preys and they have all kind of tools to survive what was
the triggering force of those was a huge question because people were
saying 'Oh you know'
'another meteoroid hit the earth' or or you know 'the environment
changed' It turned out one of the most convincing theory is by this guy
called
Andrew Parker
he's a modern zoologist in Australia from Australia he studied a lot the
fossils and he's theory is that it was the onset of the eyes so one of the
first
trilobites developed an eye, a really really simple eye it's almost like a
pinhole camera that just catches light and make some projections and
registers some information from the environment
suddenly life is no longer so mellow, because once you have the eye, the
first
thing you can do is you could go catch food you actually know where food
it's
you're not just like blind and floating in the water and once you can go
catch food
guess what the food better develop eyes and to run away from you otherwise
they'll be gone you know so the first of all who had had eyes were
like in an unlimited buffet, its like working at Google (laughter) and it's
just like they have the best time eating
everything they can but because those are onset of the eyes what we what
the
zoologist realized is the biological arms race begin every single animal
needs to
needs to learn to develop things to survive or to you know you
suddenly have preys and predators and all this and the speciation begin so
that's
when vision begun 540 million years and not only vision begun vision was
one
of the major driving force of the speciation or that the big bang of
evolution so we're not gonna follow evolution with too much detail
another big important work that focus on the engineering of vision happened
around
the Renaissance and of course it's attributed to this amazing guy Leonardo
da Vinci so before
Renaissance you know throughout human civilization from Asia to Europe to
India to Arabic world we have seen models of cameras so Aristotle has
proposed the camera through the leaves, Chinese philosopher ?? have
proposed
the camera through a box with the hole but
if you look at the first documentation really modern looking camera it's
called
camera obscura
and that is documented by Leonardo da Vinci I'm not gonna get into the
details
but this is you know you get the idea that there is some kind of a lens or
at least a hole to
capture light reflected from the real world and then there is some kind of
projection to capture the information of the real-world image so
that's the beginning of the modern you know engineering of
vision it started with wanting to copy the world and wanting to make a copy
of
the visual world it hasn't got anywhere close to wanting to engineer the
understanding of the visual world right now we're just talking about
duplicating
the visual world so that's one important work to remember and of course
after
camera obscura we start to see a whole series of successful,
some film gets developed you know like kodak was one of the first
companies developing commercial cameras and then we start to have
camcorders and
and all this Another very important piece of work that I want you
to be aware of as vision student is actually not a engineering work but
a science, piece of science work that's starting to ask the question
is "how does vision work in our biological brain ?" you know we
we now know that it took 540 million years of evolution to get a really
fantastic visual system in mammals and humans but what did evolution do
during this time
what kind of architecture did develop from that simple trilobite eye to
today
yours and mine while very important piece of work happened at Harvard by
two at that time two young two very young ambitious postdocs
Hubel and Wiesel what they did is that they used awake but anaesthetized
cats and then
there was enough technology to build this little needle called electrode to
push the
electrons through to (the skull is open) into the brain of the cat
into an area what we already know called primary visual cortex.
primary visual cortex is a area where neurons do a lot of things for visual
processing but before
Hubel and Wiesel we don't really know what primary visual cortex is doing
we just know it's
one of the earliest stage other than you eyes of course but earliest stage
for visual
processing then there is tons and tons of neurons working on vision then we
really ought to know what this is because that's the beginning of vision,
visual process in the brain so they put this electrode into the primary
visual cortex and an interestingly this is another interesting fact if I
don't all drop my
stuff I'll show you primary visual cortex the first stage or the second,
depending on where you come from, I'm being
very very rough here, first stage of your cortical visual processing stage
is
in the back of your brain not near your eye it's very interesting because
your olfactory cortical processing is right
behind your nose, your auditory is right behind your ear but your primary
visual cortex is the furthest from your eye and another very interesting
that in
fact not only the primary there's a huge area working on vision, almost 50%
of
your brain is involved in vision, vision this the hardest and most
important
sensory perceptual cognitive system in the brain and I'm not saying
anything
else is not useful clearly but it take nature this long to develop this
this sensory system and it takes the nature this much realist space to be
used for the system why because it's so important and it's so damn hard
that's
why we need to use the much space. Back to Hubel and Wiesel they were
really ambitious they wanna
know what primary visual cortex is doing because this is the beginning of
our
knowledge for deep learning neural network they were ?showing? cats, so
they put the cats in
this room and they were recording neural activities when I say recording
neural
activities they are basically trying to see you know if I put the
electrode here like do the neurons fire when they see
something? so for example if they show if they show cat ,their idea is, if
I showed cat
this fish you know apparently at that time cats eat fish rather than
these ?beings? with the cats neuron get happy and start sending spikes and
here's a
story of scientific discovery is scientific discovery takes both luck and
care and thoughtfulness they were showing this cat
fish whatever mouse flower it just doesn't work the cats neuron in the
primary
visual cortex was silent there was no spiking
very little spike and they were really frustrated but the good news is that
news is that there was no computer at that time so what they have to do
when they showed this
cats these stimuli, is they have to use a slide projector so they put his
slide
of a fish and then wait till the neuron Spike if the neuron doesn't spike
they take
the slide out putting another slide
And then they notice every rime they change slide, this squarish film, I
don't remember if they use
use glass or film whatever the neuron spikes, that's weird you know like
the
actual mouse and fish and flower didn't drive the, excite the neuron but
the movement of taking the slide out or putting a slide in did excite
the neuron It can be the cat is think "Oh finally they're changing the new
you know new objects for me". so it turned out there is an edge thats
created by this slide that
they're changing right slide the whatever it's a square rectangular plate
and that moving edge drove or excited the neurons so they're really chased
after
that observations you know if they were too frustrated or too careless,
they would have missed that
but they're not they're really chased after that and realize neurons in the
primary visual cortex are organized in columns and for every column of the
neurons
they'd like to see a specific orientation of the stimuli, simple oriented
bars
rather than fish or a mouse
you know I'm making this a bit of a simple story because there are still
numerous neurons in
primary visual cortex we don't know what they like they don't like simple
oriented but by large Hubel and Wiesel found that the beginning of
visual processing is not a holistic fish or mouse the beginning of visual
processing is simple structures of the world
edges, oriented edges and this is a very deep deep implications to both
neurophysiology / neuroscience as well as
engineering modelling it's later when we visualize our deep neural network
features
will see that simple edge-like structure emerging from our from our model
and
even though the discovery was later fifties and early sixties they won the
Nobel medical price for this work in 1981 so that was another very
important
piece of work related to vision and visual processing so when did computer
vision begin? that's another
interesting story, it's history. the precursor of computer vision as a
modern field was
this particular dissertation by Larry Roberts in 1963 it's called block
world
he just as Hubel and Wiesel we're discovering that the visual world in our
brain is organized by simple like structures Larry Roberts as early
computer science PhD
student were trying to extract these like structures
images
as a piece of engineering work in this particular case his goal is that
you know both you and I as humans can recognize blocks no matter how it's
turned right? like we know it's a same block these two are the same block
even
though the lighting changed and the orientation changed and he's
conjuncture
is that just like Hubel and Wiesel told us it's the edges that define this
the
structure that the edges define the shape and they don't change
rather than all these ?internal? things so Larry Roberts wrote a PhD
dissertation to
just extract these edges you know if your work as a PhD student computer
vision this is like you know this is like undergraduate computer vision
wouldn't
have been a PhD thesis but that was the first precursor computer vision PhD
thesis Larry Robert is interesting he gave up in computer vision afterwards
and went DARPA and was one of the inventors of the internet So he didn't do
too badly by
giving up computer vision but we always like to say that the birth of
computer
vision as a modern field is in the summer of 1966 the summer of 1966 MIT
artificial intelligence lab was established before that actually for one
piece of history you should feel proud as a Stanford student this there are
two
pioneering artificial intelligence lab established in the world in the
early
1960's one by Marvin Minsky at MIT one by John McCarthy at Stanford. At
Stanford
the artificial intelligence lab was established before the computer science
department and professor John McCarthy who founded AI lab is the one who is
responsible for
the term artificial intelligence so that's a little bit of a proud
Stanford history but anyway we have to give MIT credit for starting the
field of
computer vision because in the summer of 1966 a professor at MIT AI lab
decided it's
time to solve vision you know so AI was established we will start to
understand first order logic and
LISP was probably invented at that time but anyway
vision is so easy you open your eyes, you see the world how hard can this
be!
Lets solve this in one summer! (laughter)
MIT students are smart right? so the summer vision project is an attempt to
use our summer workers effectively in the construction of significant part
of the vision system
This was the proposal from that summer and maybe they didn't use their
summer work
effectively but in any case computer vision was not solved in that summer
since then they become the fastest growing field of computer vision and AI
if you go to today's premium computer vision conferences in CS called CVPR
or ICCV we
have like 2000 to 2500 researchers worldwide attending this conference and
very practical note for students if you are a good computer vision /
machine
learning students you will not worry about jobs in Silicon Valley or
anywhere else so it's actually one of the most exciting field but that was
the
birth day of computer vision which means this year is the fiftieth
anniversary of
computer vision that's a very exciting year in computer vision and we have
a
come a long long way
ok so continuing on the history of computer vision
this is a person to remember David Marr he was also at MIT at that time
working with a number of very influential computer vision scientists ??
Tommy Poggio. David Marr himself died
early, in the seventies He wrote a very influential book called vision it's
a very thin book
and David Marr's thinking about vision, he took a lot of insights from
neuroscience we already
said that Hubel and Wiesel give us the concept of simple structure
Vision start with
simple structure, it didn't start with a holistic fish or holistic mouse.
David Marr
give us the next important insight and these two insight together is the
beginning of deep learning architecture is that vision is hierarchical you
know
so Hubel and Wiesel said ok we start simple but Hubel and Wiesel didn't say
we end simple. This visual world is extremely
complex in fact I take a picture, a regular picture today with my IPhone
there is I don't know my iPhone's resolution let's suppose it's like 10MP
the potential combination of pixels or picture in that is bigger than the
total
number of atoms in the universe that's how complex vision can be is it's
really really complex So Hubel and Wiesel told us that start simple. David
Marr told
us build a hierarchical model. Of course david marr didn't tell us to build
it in
the convolutional neural network which will cover for the rest of the
quarter but
his ideas is to represent or to think about an image we think about it in
several layers the first one he thinks we should think about that edge
image
which is clearly an inspiration took the inspiration from Hubel and Wiesel
and
he personally called this the primal sketch
you know the name itself is self explanatory
and then you think about 2 and 1/2-D the this is where you
start to reconcile your 2d image with the 3d world you recognize there is
layers right I look at you right now I don't think half of you only has a
head
and a neck
even though that's all I see there is I know you're occluded by the row in
front of you and this is the fundamental challenge of vision. We have an
ill-posed problem to solve
nature had that ill-posed problem to solve because the world is 3d but the
imagery on our retina is 2d
nature solved it by first a hardware trick, which is two eyes it didn't use
one eye
but there's gonna be a whole bunch of software trick to merge the
information of the two eyes and all this so the same thing with computer
vision we
have to solve that 2 and a 1/2 D problem and then eventually we have to
put everything together so that we actually have a good 3d model of the
world why do we have to have a 3d model of the world as we have to survive
navigate manipulate the world when I shake your hand I really need to know
how to know
extend my hand and grab your hand in the right way that is a 3d modelling of
the world otherwise I won't be able to grab your head in the right way when
I
pick up a mug the same thing so that's David Marr's
architecture for vision that's a high-level abstract architecture it
doesn't really inform us exactly what kind of mathematical modelling we
should use
it doesn't inform us of the learning procedure and they really doesn't
inform us of the
inference procedure which we will getting into through the deep learning
network architecture but that's the high-level view of important
it's an important concept to learn
in vision and we call this the
representation A couple of really important work and this is a little bit
?? trick to
just show you as soon as David Marr laid out this important way of thinking
about vision the
first wave of visual recognition algorithms went after the 3d model
because that's the goal right like no matter how you represent the stages
the
goal here is to reconstruct that 3D model so that we can recognize object
and this is really sensible
because that's when we go to the world and do so both of these two
influential work
comes from Palo Alto one of those from Stanford one is from SRI So ?Tom?
Binford was
a professor at Stanford
AI lab and he and his student ?Rodney? Brooks proposed one of the first
so-called generalized cylinder model I'm not gonna get into the details but
the idea is that the world is composed of simple shapes like
cylinders blocks and then any real world object is just a combination of
these
simple shapes given the particular viewing angle and that was a very
influential visual recognition model in the seventies and Rodney Brook went
on to become the
Director of MIT's AI lab and he was also a founding member of iRobot
company and ??
and all this so he continued the very influential
AI work and another interesting model coming from local
Stanford Research Institute I think SRI is across the street from El Camino
is this
pictorial structure model it's very similar, it focussed, it has less of a
3d flavour but more of a probabilistic
flavour is that the objects are made of a still simple part
like a person's head is made of eyes and nose or mouth and the parts were
connected
by springs allowing for some deformations getting a sense of ok we
recognize the world not every one of you have exactly the same eyes and the
distance between the eyes we allow for some kind of variability so this
concept of variability start to get introduced in the model like this and
using models like this you know the reason I want to show you this is too
to
see how simple the work was 80s this was one of the most influential
model in the eighties recognizing real-world objects and the entire paper
of real world is these shaving razors but the using the edges and simple
shapes formed by the edges to recognize this by David Lowe, another
Stanford
graduate so that's kind of the ancient world of computer vision
we have been seeing black and white or even synthetic images. Starting the
nineties we're finally started moving to like colourful images of real world
and
what a big change. Again very very influential work here is not
particularly about recognizing an object is about how do it like carve out
an
image into sensible parts right so if you enter this room there's no way
your
visual system is tell you "Oh my god I see so many pixels" ,you immediately
have group
things you see heads heads heads, chair chair chair a staged platform, a
piece
of furniture and all this. This is called perceptual grouping perceptual
grouping is one of the
most important problem in vision, biological or artificial if we don't
know how to solve the perceptual grouping problem we're gonna have a
really hard time to deeply understand the visual world and you will learn
at the end of this class this course a problem as fundamental as the still
not
solved in computer vision even though we have made a lot of progress before
deep learning and after deep learning we're still grasping the final
solution of a problem
like this so this is again why I want to give you at this introduction to
for you to be aware of the deep problems in vision and also
the current state and the challenges in vision we did not solve all the
problems despite
whatever the news says you know like we're far from developing terminators
who can
do everything yet so this piece of work is called normalized cut is one of
the first computer vision work that takes real world images and tries to
solve a very fundamental difficult problem and ?? Malik is the senior
computer vision researcher now professor at
Berkeley also Stanford graduate
you can the results are not great Are we gonna cover any segmentation in
this class? we might right
you see we are making progress but this is the beginning of
that another very influential work that I want to bring up and pay
tribute for even though these work we're not covering them in the rest of
the
course but I think it as a vision student it's pretty important for you to
be
aware of this because not only introduces the important problem we want
to solve it also gives you a perspective of the development of the field
This work is called viola jones face detector
it's very dear to my heart because as a graduate student fresh graduate
student
at Caltech it's the one of the first papers I read as a graduate student
when
enter the lab and I didn't know anything. My advisers read this
amazing piece of work that you know we're all trying to understand and then
by
the time I graduated from Caltech this very work is transferred to the
first
smart digital camera by Fujifilm in 2006 as the first digital camera that
has a
face detector so far my technology transfer point of view it was
extremely fast and there was one of the first successful high-level visual
recognition algorithm that's being used by consumer product so this work
just
learns to detect faces and faces in the wild with no longer soon you know
simulation they are a very contrived a these are any pictures and even
though
he didn't use a deep learning network it has a lot of the deep learning
flavour
the features were learned the algorithm learns to find features simple
features
like these black and white filter features that can give us the best
localization of faces so this is a very influential piece of work it's also
one
of the first computer visual work that is deployed computer and can run
real
time before that computer vision algorithms were very slow the paper
actually is
called real-time face detection it was granted Pentium II chips I don't
know if
anybody remember that kind of chip but it was not a slow chip but
nevertheless
it run real time that was another very important piece of work and also one
more
thing to point out around this time this is not the only work
but this is a a really good representation around this time the focus of
computer vision is shifting remember that David Marr and
early Stanford work was trying to model the 3Dof the object now we're
shifting to recognizing what the object is. We lost a little bit about can
we really
reconstruct these faces or not there's a whole branch of computer vision
graphics step continue to work on that but a big part of computer vision is
not
at this time around the turn of the century is focusing on recognition
that's bringing computer vision back to AI and today the most important
parts of the
computer vision work is focused these cognitive questions like recognition
and
AI questions
another very important piece of work is starting to focus on features so
around
the time of face recognition people start to realize it's really really
hard
to recognize an object by describing the whole thing like I just said you
know I
see you guys were heavily occluded I don't see the rest of your torso I
really don't see any of your legs on it in the first row but I recognize
you and
I can infer you as an object so some people start to realize gee its not
necessary that
global shape that we have to go after in order to recognize an object
maybe it's the features if we recognize the important features an object we
can
go a long way and makes a lot of sense
think about evolution if you are out hunting you don't need to recognize
that
Tigers full body in shape to decide you need to run away you know just a
few
patches of the fur of the tiger through the
leaves probably can alarm you enough so we need to vision as quick
decision-making based on vision is really quick
a lot of this happens on important features so this work called SIFT
David Lowe again you saw that name again is about learning important
features on an object and once you learn these important features just a
few of
them on the object you can actually recognize this object in a totally
different angle on the totally cluttered scenes so up to deep learnings
resurrection in 2010 or 2012 for about 10 years the entire field of
computer vision was focusing on using these features to build models to
recognize objects and scenes and we've done a great job we've gone a long
way
one of the reasons deep learning network became more and more convincing to
a lot of people is we will see that the features that a deep learning
network
learns is very similar to these engineered features by brilliant
engineers so it kind of confirmed even know you know we needed
David Lowe to first tell us this features work and then we start to develop
better
mathematical models to learn these features by itself but they confirmed
each other so so the historical you know importance of this work should not
be
diminished this work is the intellectual foundation for us, one of the
intellectual foundation for us to realize that how critical or how useful
these deep learning features are when we learn them I'm gonna skip this
work and just briefly say because
of the features that David Lowe and many other researchers taught us we can
use
that to learn scene recognition and around that time the machine learning
tools we use mostly is either graphical models or support vector machine
and
this is one influential work on using support vector machine and kernel
models to recognize a scene but I'll be brief here and last model before
deep learning model
is this feature or feature based model called deformable part model is
where we
learn parts of object like parts of the person and we learn how they
configure
each other configure in space and use a support vector machine kind of
model to
recognize objects like humans and bottles around this time that's
2009-2010 the field of computer vision is mature enough that we're working
on this
important and hard problems like recognizing pedestrians and
recognizing cars they're no longer contrived problem something else was
needed benchmarking because as a field advanced enough if we don't have
good benchmark then everybody just publishing papers on a few set of images
and it's really hard to really
set global standard so one of the most important benchmark is called
pascal VOC object recognition benchmark its a European  effort that
researchers put together by tens of thousands of images from 20 classes of
objects and these are one example per object like cats ?? cows maybe no
cats
dogs cows airplanes bottles
horses trains
and all this and then we used and then annually our computer vision
researchers
and labs come to compete on the object recognition task for pascal VOC
object
recognition challenge and an over the past you know like through the years
the
the performance just keeps increasing and that was when we start to feel
excited about the progress of the field at that time
here's a little bit a more closer story close to us is that my lab and my
students were thinking you know the real world is not about 20 objects the
real
world is a little more than 20 objects so following the work of Pascal
visual
object recognition challenge we put together this massive massive project
ImageNet some of you may have heard of ImageNet in this class you will be
using the tiny portion of the image that in some of your assignment that
ImageNet
is the data set of 50 million images all cleaned my hands and
annotated over 20,000 object classes don't worry its not graduate students
who cleaned it (laughter) That would be very scary
It the amazon mechanical turk platform the crowdsourcing platform.
Having said that graduate students also suffered from you know putting
together this this platform
but it's a very exciting dataset and we started we started to put together
competitions annually called ImageNet competition for object recognition
and
for example a standard competition of image classification by ImageNet that
is a
thousand object classes over almost 1.5 million images and algorithms
compete on
the performance so actually I just heard somebody who was on the social
media was
referring image that challenges the Olympics of computer vision that was
very
flattering
But here is something bringing us close to the history making of deep
learning so ImageNet challenge started in 2010
that's actually around the time pascal you know where their colleagues they
told us they're gonna start to phase out their challenge of 20 object so we
phased
in the thousand object images a challenge and Y-axis is error rate
and we started with very significant error and of course you know
every year the error decreased but there is a particular year really
decreased it
was cutting ?hot? almost is 2012 2012 is the year that the winning
architecture
of image that challenge was a convolutional neural network model and we'll
talk
about it. Convolutional neural network was not invented in 2012 despite how
all the news make it sound
like it's the newest thing around the block it's not it was invented back
in
the seventies and eighties
but he's but having a convergence of things will talk about convolutional
neural network
showed its massive power as a high capacity end to end training
architecture and won the ImageNet challenged by a huge margin and that was
quite a historical moment from a mathematical point of view it wasn't
that new but from a engineering and and solving real-world point of view
this
was a historical moment that piece of work was covered by you know New York
times and all this this is the onset this is the beginning of learning
revolution if you call it and this is the premise of this class so at this
point I'm gonna switch so we went through a brief history of computer
vision for 540 million years
and I'm gonna switch to overview of this class. Is there any other
question?
alright so we're talking even though it was kind of overwhelming we talked
a lot
about finding different task in computer vision CS231n is going to focus
on the visual recognition problem also by and large especially through most
of the
foundation lecture, we are gonna talk about image
classification problem, but now you know everything we talk about is gonna
be
based on that ImageNet classification setup we will get to other
visual recognition scenarios but the image classification problem is the
main
problem we will focus on in this class which means please keep in mind
visual recognition is not just image classification right there was 3d
modelling there was a perceptual grouping and segmentation and all this but
that's
that's what we'll focus on and I don't need to convince  you that just even
application wise image classification is extremely useful problem
from you know big big commercial Internet companies app point of view to
startup ideas you know you want to recognize objects you want to recognize
food do online shop/ mobile shopping you want us sort your albums so image
classification can be a bread-and-butter task for many many
important problems there is a lot of problem that's related image
classification and
today I don't expect you to understand the differences but I want you to
hear that throughout this class
we'll make sure you learn to understand the nuances and the
the details of different flavours of visual recognition what is image
classification what's object detection what's image captioning and these
have
different flavours for example you know while image classification might
focus on the whole big image object detection might tell you where things
exactly are like where the car is the pedestrian
the hammer and the where the relationship between objects and so on
there are nuances and details that you will be learning about in this class
and I already said CNN or convolutional neural network is one type of deep
learning
architecture but it's the overwhelmingly successful deep learning
architecture and
this is the architecture we will be focusing on and to just go back to the
ImageNet challenge so I said the historical year is 2012 this is the year
that Alex Krizhevsky and his advisor Jeff Hinton proposed this
convolutional neural network I think it's a seven
layer convolutional your network to win the image that challenge model
before
this year
a SIFT feature plus support vector machine architecture it still
hierarchical
but it doesn't have that flavour of end to end learning fast forward to 2015
the winning architecture is still a convolutional neural network it's a
151 layers by microsoft Asia researchers and it's called
the residual net so I'm not so sure we're gonna cover
that definitely don't expect to know every single layer what they do
actually
they repeat itself at hard but every year since 2012 the winning
architecture
of ImageNet challenge is a deep learning based architecture so like I
said I also want you to respect history CNN is not invented overnight there
is a lot
of influential players today but you know there are a lot of people who
build
a foundation I actually I don't have the slides one important thing to
remember
is ?Kunihiko? Fukushima was a Japanese computer scientist who build a
model called Neocognitron and that was the beginning of the neural network
architecture and Yann Lecun is also a very influential person and he's
really
the ground-breaking work in my opinion of Yann Lecun was published in
the 1990s so that's when mathematicians which Jeff Hinton
Yann Lecun's PhD adviser was involved worked out the back propagation
learning
strategy which if this work didn't ?? anything Andrej will tell you in a
couple
of weeks but the mathematical model was worked out in the eighties and
90s and this was Yann Lecun was working for Bell Labs it AT&T which is
amazing place at that time there's no Bell Labs today anymore that they
were
working on really ambitious projects and he needed to recognize the digits
because eventually that product was shipped to our banks in the USA post
office to recognize zip codes and checks and he constructed those
convolutional neural network and this is where he's inspired by Hubel and
Wiesel he
starts by looking at simple edge like structures and image it's not like
the
whole letter eight it's really needs to edges and the layer-by-layer
filters these edges pool them together filters pool and then they build
this
architecture 2012 Alex Krizhevsky and Jeff Hinton used almost exactly the
same
architecture to participate in the
ImageNet challenge there is a few changes but that become the winning
architecture of this so Andrej will tell you more about the detail changes
capacity model did grow a little bit because Moore's Law helped us there's
also a very very detailed function that change the little bit of a shape
for
most Sigmoid to a Rectified Linear shape but whatever there's a couple of
small changes but really by and large nothing had changed
mathematically but important things did change and that drove deep learning
Architecture back into its Renaissance one is like I said Moore's Law and
hardware made a huge difference because these are high extremely high
capacity models When Yann Lecun was doing
this, it was painfully slow because of the bottleneck of computation he
couldn't
build this model too big a once you can't build it too big it cannot fully
realize its potential from machine learning standpoint there's overfitting
and
all these problems you can now solve but now we have much faster bigger
transistor
not transistor, microchips and GPUs from NVidia made a huge difference in
deep
learning history that we can now train these models in a reasonable amount
of time even if they're huge Another thing I think we do need to take
credit for
is data availability of data that was the big data did itself is just you
know it doesn't mean anything if you don't know how to use it but in this
deep learning Architecture data become the driving force for high-capacity
model to enable end-to-end training to help avoid overfitting when
you have enough data so you know so you if you look at the number of pixels
that
machine learning people had in 2012 versus Yann Lecun having 1998 it's a
huge
difference
orders of magnitude so this is the focus of 231n
but will also go oh it's also important one last time I'm drill in this
idea
that visual intelligence does go beyond object recognition I don't want any
of
you coming out of this course thinking "We've done everything you know
we've solved vision"
and the ImageNet challenge defined the entire space of visual recognition
it's not true there
are still a lot of cool problems to solve for example you know dense
labelling
entire scene with perceptual grouping so I know where every single pixel
belonged
that's still ongoing problem, combining
recognition with 3d is a really there's a lot of excitement happening at
the
intersection of vision and robotics this is definitely one area of that
and then anything to do with motion ?? and this is another
big open area of research work I put this here because Justin is heavily
involved in this work, beyond putting labels in the scene you actually want
deeply understand a picture
what people are doing what are the relationship between objects in then we
start getting
into the relation between objects and this is an ongoing project
called visual genome in my lab that Justin and the number of my students
are
involved and this goes far beyond image classification of we talked about
and what is one of our Holy Grails while one of the Holy Grails of computer
vision is want
to be able to tell the story of a scene right so I think about you as a
human
you open your eyes
the moment you open your eyes you're able to describe what you see in fact
in
psychology experiments we find that even if you show people this picture
for only
five hundred milliseconds that's literally half of the second people who
write essays about it we pay them $10 an hour so they didn't (laughter)
it wasn't that long but you know I figure if we talked more money they
probably could write longer essays but the point is that our visual system
is
extremely powerful we can tell stories and I would dream of this is my
challenge to Andrej's
dissertation that can we give you, give a computer one picture and out
comes a
description like this you know I was getting there you'll see work that
give the
computer one picture, it gives you one sentence or you give the computer
one picture it turns
into a bunch of short sentences but we're not here yet but that's one of
the Holy Grail
and the other Holy Grail is continuing this i think is
is summarized really well by Andrej's blog is you know take a picture like
this right
the stories are so refined there so much nuance in this picture that you
get to enjoy not only
you recognize the ?? it will be very boring if all computer can tell you is
man man man room scale mirror
whatever cabinet locker that's it you know here you recognize what they
are recognized the trick
Obama is doing you recognize the kind of interaction you recognize the
humour you
recognize there's just so much nuance that this is what the world is about
we
used our ability to visual understanding to not only survive navigate
manipulate
but we use it to socialize to entertain to understand, to learn the world
and
this is where vision, grand goals of vision that is so and I
don't need to convince you that computer visual technology will make our
world a
better place despite some scary talks out there you know even ??
today in the industry as well as research world we're using computer
vision to build better robots to save lives to go deep exploring and all
this now
ok so I have like what two minutes 3?, 5 minutes left
great time let me introduce the team Andrej and Justin are the co-
instructors with
me TAs please stand up to say hi everybody
can you like just say your name quickly and you're like what year just
don't give
a speech but yes ?? ??
Cool so these are the heroes behind the scene and please stay in touch with
us, there are two really the best way and almost want to say the only way
and i'll tell you what's the exception. Stay in touch through piazza.
Anything course related please please do not send any of us personal emails
because I'm just gonna say this, If you dont hear replies or your issues
are not solved I'm really sorry because this is a 300+ peoples class
Our this mailing list actually tags our emails and helps us to process. The
only time I respect you to send a personal email mostly to me and Andrej
and Justin is
confidential personal issues. I understand if you don't want that to be
broadcasted to a team of 10 TAs, thats ok but that should be really really
minimal. That should be the only time you send us email. And also again I'm
going on a maternity leave for a
few weeks starting the end of January so please if you decide you just
want to send email to me unless its my like due date for a baby
I'm likely to a reply you promptly sorry about that
priorities! (laughter)
So a couple of words about our philosophy We're not getting to the details
we really want
this to be a very hands-on project this is really I give a lot of credit to
Justin and Andrej they are extremely good at walking through these hands-on
details with you so that when you come out of this class you not only have
a
high-level understanding but you have thorough you have a really good
ability to build
your own deep learning code we want you to be exposed to state of the art
material you're gonna be learning things really that's as fresh as 2015 and
it'll
be fun you get to do things like this
Not all the time but like time the picture into Van Gough or this weird
thing it'll be a fun class in addition to all the important tasks you
learn we do have grading policies these are all on our website
I'm not gonna iterate this Again one thing I'm gonna be very clear,
actually two things. One is late policy you are grown ups we treat you like
grown-ups we do not take anything at the end of the course "Oh my
professors want
me to go to this conference and I have to have like three more late days"
No
you are responsible for using your total late days you have 7 late you can
use
them in whatever way you want with 0 penalty beyond those you have to take
a penalty
Unless its like really really exceptional medical family emergency
talk to us on the individual basis but anything else
conference deadlines other final exams you know like missing cat or
whatever is
we budgeted that into the seven days another thing is honor code this is
one
thing I have to say it with a really straight face you are in such a
privileged
institution you are grown ups I want you to be responsible for honor
code every single Stanford student taking this class should know the honor
code
if you don't there's no excuse you should go back
we take collaboration extremely seriously I almost hate to say that
statistically
given a class this big were gonna have a few cases but I also want you to
be an
exceptional class even with a size this big we do not want to see anything
that
infringes on Academic Honor Code so read the collaboration policies and
respect that
this is really respecting yourself I think with all these prereq you can
you can read it yourself I'm done with anything I want to say is there any
burning
questions that you feel worth asking? yes ?? ??