#Done till 00:05:31
and we're recording as well. Ok great just
remind you again
hello we're recording the classes so if you're uncomfortable
speaking on camera, you're
not in the picture but your voice might be
on the recording ok great as you can
see also the screen is wider than it should
be and I'm not sure how to fix it
so you'll have to live with it
luckily your visual cortex is very good, its
very invariance to stretching so
this is not a problem
ok so we'll start out with some administrative things
before we dive into the class the
first assignment will come out tonight or
early tomorrow it is due in January
20, so you have exactly two weeks you will be writing
a kNN classifier, a linear classifier
and a small two-layer neural network you'll
be writing the entirety of
backpropagation algorithm for 2 layer neural
network we'll cover all that
material in next two weeks and warning by
the way there are assignments from last
year as well and we're changing the assignments
so they will please do not
complete in 2015 assignment that's something
to be aware of and for your
computation we'll be using Python and
numpy and we'll also be offering
terminal.com which is which is basically
the virtual machines in the
cloud that you can use if you don't have a
very good laptop and so on
I'll go into detail of that in a bit i just like to
point out that for the first
assignment we assume that you'll be relatively
familiar with Python you'll
be writing these optimized numpy expressions
where you at manipulating
these matrices and vectors and very efficient
forms so for example if you're
seeing this code and its doesn't mean anything
to you then please have a look
at our python tutorial that is up on the website
as well it's written by Justin
and is very good and so go through that and
familiarize yourself with the
notation because you'll be seeing you writing
a lot of code that looks like
this where we doing all these optimize operations
so they're fast enough to run
on the CPU now in terms of terminal basically
what this amounts to is that
will give you a link to the assignment you'll
go to a web page and you'll see
something like this this is a virtual machine
in the cloud that has been set
up with all the dependencies of the assignment
they're all installed already
on the data is already there and so you click
on launch machine and this'll
basically bring you to something like this
this is running your browser and
this is basically a thin layer on top of an
AWS
machine a UI layer here and so you have an
iPython notebook and a little
terminal and you can go around and this is
just like a machine in the cloud and
so they have some CPU offerings and they also
have some GPU machines that you can
use and so on
normally have to pay for terminal but will
be distributing credits to you so
you just lost to a specific TA that will decide
in a bit you email to a TA and
ask for money will send you money and we keep
track of how much money we sent to
all the people so you have to be responsible
with the funds so this is
also an option for you to use you like ok
any details
are you can you can read
you ca write it if you like
it if you like it's not required for your
assignment
but you can probably get there around yeah
ok I'm just gonna dive in to the lecture now
lecture now today we'll be talking about which
classification and specially will
start off on linear classifiers so we talk
about the classification the basic
task is that we have some number of categories
say dog cat truck plane or so
on we get to decide what these are and then the task earlier to take an image
which is a giant grid of numbers and we have
to transform into one of these
labels we have to bin it into one of the
categories this problem will spend
most of our time talking about this one specifically
but if you'd like to do any
other task in computer vision such as detection
image capture any segmentation
or whatever else you'll find that once he
know about the classification and how
that's done everything else is just the tiny
delta on top of it so you'll be in
a great position to do any of the other tasks
so it's really good for conceptual
understanding and we'll work through that
as a specific example to simplify
things in the beginning now why is this problem
hard just give an idea the
problem is what we refer to as a semantic
gap this image here as a giant
grid of numbers the way the images are represented
in the computer is that this
is basically say roughly 300x100x3 pixels array
, so a 3D array and threes from the three
color channels red green and blue
and so when you zoom in on the part of that
image is basically a giant grid of
numbers between 0 and 255 so that's what we
have to work with these numbers
indicate the amount of brightness in all
the three color channels at every
single position in the image and so the reason
that image classification is
difficult
when you think about what we have to work
with decent like millions of
numbers of that form and having to classify
things like cats it quickly
became apparent to the complexity of the task
so for example the camera can be
rotated around this cat and it can be zoomed
in and out, rotated shifted the
focal properties and intrinsic of that camera
can do different and think about
what happens to the brightness values
in this grid as you actually do all
these transformations with a camera it'll completely
shift, all the patterns are
changing and we have to be robust to all of this
there are also many other
challenges for example charges up illumination
here we have a long cat
white cat we actually have two of them but
you can't see the other one So one cat is
basically illuminated quite a bit and the other
is not but you can still recognize
two cats and so think about again the brightness
values on the level of the
grid and what happens to them as he changed
all the different lightings and all
the possible lighting schemes that we can
have in the world with to be robust
to all that there's issues of deformation
many classes lots of strange
arrangement of these objects would like to
recognize so cats coming very
different poses with the slides when I create
them they're quite dry there's a
5:37
lot of math and science this is the only time
I get to have fun so that's what I
5:41
just somehow everything that occurs to be
robust to all of these affirmations
5:45
you can still recognizes the cat and all of
these images despite their problems
5:50
so sometimes we might not see the pelagic
but you still recognizes that's
5:54
cat the cat behind a water bottle and there's
also a cab there inside a couch
6:00
even though you're seeing just 10 PCs pieces
of this class basically there's
6:06
problems on background clutter so things can
blend into the environment we have
6:10
to be reminded that and there's also the intra-class
variation so cat actually
6:15
there's a huge amount of cats just species
and so they can look different
6:19
ways with your boss to all of that so i just
like you to appreciate the
6:23
complexity of the task we consider any one
of these independently is difficult
6:26
but when you consider the cross product of
all these different things and have
6:31
to work across all of that it's actually quite
amazing that anything works at all
6:35
in fact not only does it work but it works
really really well almost here
6:39
accuracy of categories like this and we can
do that in a few dozen milliseconds
6:43
with the current technology and so that's
what you learn about this class
6:49
classifier look like basically we're taking
this through the area we'd like
6:54
to produce a class label and when i'd like
he's noticed that there is no
6:57
obvious way up actually encoding and you'll
this of these classifiers right
7:01
there's no simple algorithm like say you're
taking it all good in class early
7:04
computer science curriculum your writing bubble
sort or you're writing something
7:08
else to do any particular task you can intuit
all the possible steps and you
7:11
can enumerate them and lets them and play
with it and analyze it but here
7:15
there's no algorithm for detecting a cat under
all these variations are it's
7:18
extremely difficult to think about how you
actually write that up what is the
7:21
sequence of operations you would do an arbitrary
image to detect a cat that's
7:26
not to say that people haven't tried especially
early these a computer but
7:28
there were these explicit approaches as I'd
like to call them where you think
7:32
about okay I can't say is that he would like
to meet you look for little ear
7:37
pieces so what we'll do is we'll detect all
the edges UltraISO edges will
7:40
classify the different traits of edges and
their junctions will create you know
7:45
libraries of the season will try to find their
arrangements and if we ever see
7:48
anything like that will detect the cat we
see any particular texture of some
7:52
particular frequencies will attack the cat
as you can come up with some rules
7:55
but the problem is that once I tell you okay
I'd like to actually recognize the
7:59
boat now or a person when you go back to the
drawing board and yet to be like ok
8:03
what makes a boat exactly what the original
pages right it's completely
8:06
scalable approach to to prosecution as the
pressure dropping this class and
8:11
approach that works much better as the data-driven
approach that we like in the
8:16
framework of machine learning and just to
point out that in these days actually
8:20
in the early days they did not have the luxury
of using data because at this
8:23
point in time you're taking your grayscale
images of very low resolution
8:27
images in your trying to recognize things
it's obviously not going to work
8:30
but with the availability of Internet huge
amount of data I can search for
8:33
example for cat on Google and I get lots of
cats everywhere and we know that
8:38
these are cats based on the surrounding text
in the web pages so there's a lot
8:42
of data so the way that this now looks like
is that we have a training face
8:46
where you give me lots of training samples
cast
8:49
and you tell me about their cats you give
me lots of examples of any type of
8:52
other category you're interested in
8:54
I do I go away and I trained to model a model
is a class and I can then use that
8:59
model to actually classified data so what
i'm given a new image I can look at
9:04
my training data and I can do something with
this based on just a pattern
9:07
matching and statistics or someone so as a
simple example will work within this
9:13
framework consider the nearest neighbor classifier
the way you're single
9:17
classifier works is that effectively were
given destroyed Trade Center will
9:20
do a training time as well just remember all
the training data so have all the
9:23
training data just got here and I remember
it now when you give me a test
9:27
image what we'll do is we'll compare the test
image to every single one of the
9:32
images we saw in a train data and we'll just
transfer the label over so I'll
9:36
just look through all the images will work
with specific case as I go through
9:41
this I like to be as complete as possible
so we'll work with a specific
9:43
case of something called Seifert India set
the scene for today as it has 10
9:47
labels labels there are 50,000 training images
that you have access to and then
9:53
there's a test set of 10 10,000 images where
we're going to evaluate how well
9:57
the classifiers working and these images are
quite tiny they're just little to a
10:00
dataset of 32 by 32 little thumbnail images
so the wait nearest neighbor
10:05
classifier would work as we take all this
training did others given to us
10:07
fifty thousand just not just i'm suppose we
have these ten different examples
10:12
here is our test images along the first call
in here what we'll do is we'll look
10:15
up the nearest neighbors in the training set
of things that are most similar to
10:19
every one of those in just independently so
there you see a ranked list of images
10:24
that are most similar to into training data
to any one of those 10 to every one
10:30
of those test images over there so in the
first row will see that there's a
10:32
truck i think is a test image and there's
quite a few images that look
10:36
similar to it will see how exactly where to
find similar teeny bit but you can
10:40
see that the first retreat result is in fact
a horse not a truck and that's
10:44
because of just the arrangement of the blue
sky that was thrown off so you can
10:48
see that this will not probably work very
well how do we define this is
10:52
measured how do we actually do the comparison
there are several ways one of
10:55
the simplest ways might be a Manhattan distance
so and understands or Manhattan
10:59
distance of the Institute
11:01
terms interchangeably simply what it does
is you have a test image you're
11:04
interested in classifying and considered one
single training image that we want
11:07
to compare this image to see what we'll do
is we'll element price compare all
11:11
the pics lollies so will form the absolute
value differences and then we
11:15
just add all that up so we're just look at
every single position or subtracting
11:20
it off and see what the differences are increasingly
special position adding it
11:24
all up and that's our similarity so these
two images are for 56 different so
11:30
we get a zero if we have identical images
here just to show your code
11:33
specifically the way this would look like
this is a full implementation of a
11:36
nearest-neighbor classifier and where I filled
in the actual body of the two men
11:42
talked about and what we do here at training
time as we're giving this
11:46
dataset X and Y which usually the note the
labels so forgiving and labels all
11:52
we do is just assigned to the class instance
methods so just remembered the
11:56
data nothing is being done I predict time
though what we're doing here is
12:01
we're getting newt test set of images X and
I'm not going to go through a full
12:06
details but you can see there's a for loop
over every single test image
12:09
independently we're getting the distances
to every single training image
12:13
and notice that that's only a single line
of vector I used Python code so in
12:18
a single line of code were comparing that
test image to every single training
12:21
image in the database computing this distance
in a previous slide and I think
12:26
alike so that's a crisis code we didn't have
to expend all those four loops that
12:30
are involved in processing systems and then
we compute the instance that is
12:35
closest so we're getting them in index the
index of the training that is has
12:40
the lowest distance and then we'll just predicting
for this image the label of
12:45
whatever so here's a question for you in terms
of the nearest neighbor classifier
12:51
how does its speed depend on the training
data size what happens is a
12:56
scale up the training gear slower
13:02
yes it's actually it's actually really slow
right because if I have I just have
13:07
to compare every single training sample independently
so it's a little slow down
13:12
and actually go as we go through the classes
that this is actually backwards
13:16
because what we really care about the most
practical applications as we care
13:19
about the test time performance of these classifiers
that means that we want this
13:23
class to be very efficient at this time and
so there's a tradeoff between really
13:27
how much computer we put on the train method
and how much do we put in a good
13:30
nearest neighbor is instant a train but then
it's expensive a test and as we'll
13:35
see soon come that's actually flip this completely
the other way around
13:38
will see that we do a huge amount of compute
a train time will be training
13:41
commercial network system performance will
be super efficient in fact it will
13:45
be constant amount of compute for every single
test image with the constant
13:49
amount of computation no matter if you have
a million billions or trillions
13:53
training I'm just I'd like to have a trillion
trillion trillion trillion just
13:57
no matter how large or trade deficit will
do a complete custom computer to
14:01
classify any single testing sample so that's
very nice practically speaking
14:05
now I'll just like to point out that there
are ways of speeding up here saber
14:10
classifiers there's these approximate nearest
neighbor methods plan as an
14:13
example library that people use up to practice
that allows you to speed up
14:16
this process of nearest-neighbor matching
but that's just a side note ok
14:22
so let's go back to the design of the classifier
we saw that we've defined
14:27
this distance and I arbitrarily chosen to
show you the Manhattan distance which
14:32
compares the difference of the absolute value
there is in fact many ways you can
14:35
formulate a distance metric and so there's
many different choices of
14:38
exactly how we do this comparison another
sim another choice to people
14:42
like to use in practice is what we call the
Euclidean are ultra distance which
14:46
instead sums up the differences in the sums
of squares of these differences
14:49
between images and so this choice
14:55
that someone over there and back
15:02
ok so this choice of what how exactly computer
distance it's a discrete choice
15:07
that we have control over that something we
called hyper primary it's not really
15:11
obvious how you set it it's a hyper parameters
we have to decide later on
15:14
exactly how to set this somehow another sort
of hybrid primary they'll talk
15:19
about in context of a classifier is when we
generalize nearest neighbor to have
15:22
what we call a k nearest neighbor classifier
so in a que horas neighbor
15:26
classifiers that are retrieving for every
test match the single nearest
15:29
train example will in fact retreat several
examples and will have the new
15:33
majority vote over the closest to actually
classified every test instance
15:37
so say a neighbor we would be retrieving the
five most similar images in the
15:41
training data and doing a majority vote of
the labels here's a simple
15:45
two-dimensional data set to illustrate the
point so here we have a three-class
15:48
dataset and 2d and Here I am drawing what
we call decision regions this
15:53
nearest neighbor classifier here with this
refers to is were truly trained
15:57
over there and we're coloring the entire to
deplane by what class this nearest
16:02
neighbor classifier with a sign that every
single point suppose you don't
16:05
suppose you had a test example some more here
than just saying that this would
16:08
have been classified as blue class based on
the nearest neighbor you get personal
16:12
note that here is a point that is a green
point inside the blue cluster and
16:16
it has its own little region of class where
it would have classified a lot of
16:19
tests place around it as green because if
anything to tell their than that
16:23
green point of the nearest neighbor now when
you move to higher numbers for ke
16:27
such as five years neighbor classifier what
you find is that the boundaries
16:30
start to smooth out it's kind of nice effect
where even that there's just one
16:36
point
16:37
kind of randomly as noise and outliers in
the blue cluster it's actually not
16:41
employing the predictions too much because
we always are treating five
16:44
nearest neighbors and so they get to overwhelm
the Greenpoint so in practice
16:49
you'll find that usually can your summer classifiers
offer better better
16:53
performance at US time now but again the choice
of k is again a hyper perimeter
16:58
right so I'll come back to this in a bit just
to show you an example of this look
17:03
like here I'm returning ten most similar examples
they're ranked by their
17:06
distance and I would actually do majority
vote over these training
17:08
examples here to classify every test example
here
17:13
ok so let's do a bit of questions here just
consider what is the accuracy of
17:20
the north of a classifier on the training
data when we're using Euclidean
17:24
distance so I suppose our test set is exactly
the training data and we're
17:29
trying to find the accuracy in other words
how many how often would we get
17:32
the correct answer
17:34
hundred-percent good ok among numerous yeah
that's correct so we're always find
17:44
a train example exactly on top of that test
which has their own this does and
17:48
then it's like will be transferred over what
if we're using the Manhattan
17:52
distance that
18:00
Manhattan distance doesn't need sum of squares
are you some absolute values
18:04
from differences it would it's just a question
would be something like a good
18:12
summer or keeping
18:14
attention ok what is the accuracy of the King
your neighbor classifier trained it
18:18
is a cable spot if is it a hundred percent
not necessarily get because
18:25
basically the points around you could overwhelm
you even have your best
18:29
example is actually off the glass ok so we've
discussed two choices of different
18:35
premise we have just met Rick its high pressure
in this case we're not sure how
18:39
to set it should be 1 23 10 and so on so we're
not exactly sure how to set these
18:45
in fact their problem dependent you'll find
that you can't find consistently
18:48
best choice for these high premise in some
applications some case might look
18:52
better than other applications so we're not
really sure how to set this so
18:56
here's an idea we have to basically try out
to lots of different primers so I'm
19:00
gonna do as I'm going to take my train data
and then I'm going to try out lots
19:05
of different parameters so I might just die
and I try out cables 123456 2800 I
19:11
tried all the defendants metrics and whatever
works best that's what I'll
19:14
take so that will work very well right lies
in its not a good idea because ok
19:26
so basically so basically yes so test data
is your proxy for your
19:36
generalization of your order them you should
not trust should the test data in
19:40
fact you should forget that you ever have
to Stata so it went 1 for giving
19:43
your dataset always set aside the testator
pretend you don't have it
19:46
that's telling you how will your organs generalizing
to unseen data points and
19:50
is important because you're trying to develop
your algorithm and then you're
19:52
hoping to eventually the planet and some setting
and you liked understanding of
19:56
exactly how will do I expect this to work
in practice right and so you'll see
20:01
that for example sometimes you can perform
very very well-intended about
20:03
not generalize very well to test it on
20:05
you're overthinking someone a lot of this
by 28 to 29 the requirement for
20:08
this class so you should be quite familiar
with this disease to most
20:11
extent this is kind of more and more overview
for you but basically this test
20:16
data is used very sparingly forget that you
have it instead what we do is we
20:20
separate our training data into what we call
folds so we separate safely use a
20:25
five-fold validation so we use twenty percent
of the training data as a
20:29
imagine such data and then we only training
part of it and we test on we
20:35
just have two choices applied primarily on
this validation set so I'm going to
20:39
train on my phone calls and try out different
case and all the front of some
20:42
clerics and whatever else if you're using
approximate nearest neighbor yet
20:45
many other choices you try it out see what
works best on that validation data
20:48
if you're feeling uncomfortable because you
have very few training data points
20:51
people also sometimes used cross-validation
where you actually get
20:54
to rate the choice of your test validation
pulled across these choices
20:58
so I'll first use for 124 for my training
and try out on five and then I
21:03
cycled the choice of the validation pulled
across all the five choices and I
21:07
look at what works best across all the possible
choices of my test fold and
21:11
then I just take whatever works best across
all the possible scenarios
21:14
that's a front-runner cross validation set
screw validation some practice the
21:19
way this would look like they were Cross building
for K for nearest neighbor
21:21
classifier is we are trying out different
values of K and this is our
21:26
performance across five choices of the fold
so you can see that for every
21:31
single case we have five data points there
and then this is the accuracy so
21:35
high is good and I'm plotting a line through
the mean analyst Sean Arce for
21:40
the standard deviations so we see here is
that the performance goes up on the
21:44
across these polls as you go up but at some
point starr said idk so for this
21:49
particular dataset it seems that K equal to
7 is the best choice so that's what
21:53
I'll do this for all my hyperemesis also for
the symmetric and so on I do my
21:58
cross validation i promise i said i fix them
evaluate a single time on the test
22:03
site and whatever number I get to that's what
I report as eight accuracy of a
22:07
king or some classifier on this dataset that's
what goes into a paper that's
22:11
what goes into our final report as long as
the final generalization result of
22:15
what you've done
22:16
any questions about this
basically it's about the statistics of the
distribution
22:36
of these data points in your label in your
face and so sometimes it's hard to
22:42
say like you get whereas this picture you
see roughly what happening as you
22:47
get more cleanliness and more case and it
just depends on how clunkier data
22:52
service that's really what it comes down to
is how
22:55
lobby is it or how specific is it I know that's
very handy answer but that's
23:01
roughly what what that comes into so different
datasets will have different
23:04
clicking us
right now
23:27
because
23:31
and different different datasets will require
different choices and need to
23:37
see what works best if actually try out different
algorithms
23:40
you're not sure what's going to work best
in your data the choice of your
23:43
order is also kind of like hyper hammer so
you're just not sure what works
23:47
different approaches will be different
23:52
generalization boundaries they look different
and some data sets up the
23:55
front structure than other some things work
better than others
23:58
just ran it tried out ok I just like to point
out that king or something worse
24:05
is no one basically uses this sunday going
through this just doesn't get used
24:09
to this approach of really how this works
with training just splits and so
24:12
on
24:13
the reason this is never used as because first
of all it's very inefficient but
24:17
second of all this is my tracks all images
which are very high dimensional
24:21
objects they acting very unnatural and intuitive
ways I've done is taken in
24:28
order to limit and I change it in three different
ways but all these three
24:32
different images here have actually the exact
same distance to this one in an L
24:37
to Euclidean sense as I just think about this
one here is slightly shifted to the
24:42
left it's dropped slightly and it's this is
here are completely different because
24:46
these pixels are not matching up exactly and
it's all introducing all these
24:49
errors in your getting distance this one is
slightly darkened so you get a small
24:53
Delta across all special occasions and this
one is untouched 60 distance eres
24:57
across everywhere except in those positions
over there and that is taken
25:01
out critical pieces of the image and it doesn't
the nearest neighbor classifier
25:05
will not be able to really tell the difference
between these settings
25:08
because it's based on these distances that
don't really work very well in this
25:11
case so very unintuitive things happen when
you try to throw distances on very
25:16
high dimensional objects that's partly why
we don't exist so in summary so far
25:21
we're looking at these classifications a specific
case involving two different
25:26
settings later in the class of Engineers neighbor
classifier and the idea of
25:29
having different splits up your data and we
have these high pressure hose that
25:33
will need to pick and we use Cross foundation
for this usually most of the
25:37
time people don't actually entire cross-validation
they just have a single
25:39
validation
25:40
and they try out on the validation set whatever
works best in terms of the high
25:43
premise and once you get the best have primaries
you have a lead to single
25:47
tenant just said so I'm going to go into the
classification but any questions at
25:54
this point I see great we're going to look
at Telenor classification this is a
26:04
point where we are starting to work towards
commercial networks it'll be a
26:07
series of lectures will snarl classification
that will build up to an
26:11
entire commercial network analyzing image
I just like to say that motivated
26:15
the class yesterday from a task-specific view
this class is computer vision class
26:20
interested in giving machines site and other
way to motivate this class will be
26:25
from a model-based point of view in a sense
that we're giving you guys
26:29
watching guys about the plumbing and electrics
these are wonderful algorithms
26:34
that you can apply to many different demands
not just some particularly over
26:38
the last few years we saw that neural networks
can not only see that's what
26:42
you'll learn a lot about this class but he
also here there is quite a bit in a
26:46
speech recognition now so when you talk to
your phone does not work they can
26:50
also do machine translation so here you are
feeding neural network a set of
26:56
words one by one in English and the neural
network produces the translation
27:00
in print or whatever else target language
you have to perform control so
27:05
we've seen your network applications and manipulate
in the robots manipulation
27:09
and playing at a party gains work learn how
to play three games just by seeing
27:14
the rockets will set the screen and we seem
to be very successful in the
27:18
variety of domains and even more than a bit
here and we're uncertain exactly
27:23
where this will take us and then I'd like
to also say that we're exploring
27:27
ways for lyrics do think that this is very
henry VIII is just wishful thinking
27:31
but there are some hints that maybe they can
do that as well
27:35
neural networks are very nice because they're
just fun modular things to play
27:39
with when I think about working with their
networks I kind of this picture
27:42
comes to mind for me here we have a neural
networks practitioner and she's
27:46
building what looks to be a roughly 10 layer
at this point
27:51
it's very fun really the best way to think
about playing with their looks
27:55
like Lego blocks you'll see that we're building
these little function pieces
27:58
you look a lot so we can stuck together to
create entire architectures and then
28:02
very easily talk to each other and so we can
just create these modules in
28:06
Stockton together and play with this very
easily won work that I think
28:11
exemplifies this is my homework on which captioning
from roughly a year ago so
28:16
here in the task was to take an image and
you're trying to get to work to
28:20
produce a sentence description of the image
so for example the top left these
28:23
artists set results would say that this is
many black shirt was playing guitar
28:27
or a construction worker in Orange City West
is working on the road and so on so
28:32
they can look at the image and create this
description of every single image
28:36
and when you go to the details of this model
the way this works is we're taking
28:41
the convolutional neural network which we
know so there's two modules here in
28:45
this system diagram for image capturing model
which we can accomplish on your
28:49
network which we know can see we're taking
a recurrent neural network which
28:52
we know is very good and modeling sequences
in this case sequences of
28:56
words that will be describing the image and
then just as if we were playing with
28:59
LEGOs we take those two pieces and we stick
them together its corresponding to
29:02
this arrow here in between the two modules
in these networks learned to
29:06
talk to each other and in the process of trying
to describe the images these
29:10
gradients will be flown through the comedy
show that work on the phone
29:13
system will be adjusting itself to better
see the images in order to
29:16
describe them at the end and so this whole
system will work together as one
29:20
so we'll be working towards this model will
actually come to this class will
29:24
have a full understanding exactly off both
this part and this part about
29:28
halfway through the course roughly you'll
see how that instructional model
29:31
works but that's just a motivation for really
what we're building up to and
29:34
you're like really nice models to work with
ok but for now back to see 410 and
29:40
all your classification
29:43
just remind you are working with this dataset
2000 and Justin labels and we're
29:47
going to approach your classification is from
what we call a parametric approach
29:50
can remember that we just discussed now is
something an instance of what we call
29:55
nonparametric approach there's no parameters
that we're going to be
29:57
optimizing over this distinction will become
clearer and human it's also
30:02
apparent to the project we're doing is worth
30:04
thinking about constructing a function that
takes an image and produces the
30:09
scores for classes right this is what we want
to do you want to take any image
30:12
and we'd like to figure out which one of the
ten plus it is so we'd like to write
30:17
down the function and expression that takes
an image and gives you those two
30:21
numbers but the expression is not only function
of that image but critically
30:24
ill be also a function of these parameters
that are called W sometimes
30:28
also called the weights so really it's a function
that goes from 3072 numbers
30:33
which make up this image to 10 numbers that's
what we're doing we're defining a
30:37
function and we'll go through several choices
of this function in this in the
30:42
first case will look at later functions and
then extended to control it works
30:45
and then we'll extend that to get commercial
networks but intuitively what
30:49
we're building up to is that what we'd like
is when we put this image through
30:53
our function we'd like the 10 numbers that
correspond to the scores of the 10
30:57
closest would like the number that corresponds
to the cat class to be high
31:01
and all the other numbers to be low and will
have we don't have a choice over X
31:06
that acts as our image that's given a choice
over W you will be free to set
31:11
aside whatever we want and we want will want
to set it to let this function
31:15
gives us the correct answers for every single
image in our training data that's
31:19
roughly the approach we're building towards
suppose that we use the simplest
31:23
the simplest just a linear classification
here so X is our image in
31:29
this case wrongdoing as I'm taking this array
this image that makes up the cat
31:34
and I'm stretching out with all the pixels
in that image into a giant column
31:38
vector so that there is a column vector of
3072 numbers and so if you know your
31:46
matrix vector operations which you should
that's a prerequisite for this
31:52
class that there is just a matrix multiplication
which should be familiar
31:55
with and basically we're taking X which is
a 3072 muscle column vector we're
32:00
trying to get 10 numbers and it no longer
function so you can go backwards
32:03
and figure out the dimensions of this w are
basically 10 by 3072 so there are
32:08
30,000 772 202 numbers that goes into W and
that's what we have control over
32:14
that's what we have to tweak and find what
works
32:16
so those are the parameters in this particular
case when I'm leaving out is
32:21
there's also an appended + be sometimes so
you have a bias these biases are
32:26
against 10 more parameters and we have to
also find those so usually in a
32:31
linear classifier have a WNB we have to find
exactly what works best and this
32:36
baby is not a function of the image that's
just independent waits on the on
32:39
how likely any one of those just might be
to go back to your question if you
32:44
have a very unbalanced datasets for so maybe
you have mostly cats but some dogs
32:50
or something like that then you might expect
that the cat the bias for the
32:54
catalyst might be slightly higher because
by default the classifier once
32:58
to predict the catalyst unless something comes
to the otherwise something in the
33:04
image of God this otherwise I think that's
more concrete I just like to
33:08
break it down but of course I can't visualize
it very explicitly width 3072
33:11
numbers so imagine that our input image 1024
pixels and imagine so more pics
33:17
also stressed out in the column X and imagine
that we have three classes so
33:21
red green and blue costs or a cat adoption
process so in this case W will
33:27
be only a three by for matrix and what we're
doing here is we're trying to
33:30
compute the score of this major acts so this
is major application going on here
33:36
to give us the output of path which is this
course we got the three scores for
33:40
three different classes so this is random
setting up w just running mates
33:45
here and we'll get some scores some particularly
can see that with this this
33:50
setting up w is not very good right because
with this setting up w Marquette
33:55
score of 96 is much less than any of the other
classes right so this was not
34:00
correctly classified for this training image
so that's not a very good
34:04
classifier so we want to change a different
double
34:07
want to use a different W so that that score
comes up higher than the other
34:10
ones but we have to do that consistently across
the entire training such examples
34:14
but one thing to notice here as well as the
basically W
34:20
it's this function is in parallel evaluating
all the tenant classifiers
34:25
but really there are ten independent classifiers
34:28
to some extent here and every one of these
classifiers like say the cats
34:32
classifier is just a first row of W here right
in the first row and the first
34:36
bias gives you can't score and the dog classifier
is the second row W and the
34:41
ship's quarter the ship + 500 W W matrix has
all these different classifier
34:46
stacked and rose and they're all being docked
product and with the image to
34:50
give you this course so here's a question
for you what does a linear
34:56
classifier do in English we saw the functional
form sticking is doing this
35:02
funny operation there what was really interpret
and English somehow what this
35:07
is doing
35:28
X being a high-dimensional data point and
W is really putting plains through
35:39
the site and come back to that interpretation
of it but either way can
35:43
we think about this team way where every single
one of these rows of W
35:59
effectively is like this template that we're
not talking with the image and I
36:03
dot product is really a way of like natural
up seeing what what Alliance get
36:08
to what other ways
36:17
two positions because what we can do is some
of the spatial positions index if
36:42
we have zero weights then the classifier would
be
36:44
doesn't care what's in part of image so 50
waits for this part here then nothing
36:50
affected but for some other parts of the image
of you have positive or negative
36:53
weights something's gonna happen there and
contribute to the score in other
36:58
ways of describing
a space to a label space
37:23
so
the question so this image as a three-dimensional
terrain where we have
37:33
all these channels you just a stretcher doubts
all the you stretch it out in
37:37
whatever way you like say you start the red
green and blue portions side-by-side
37:41
only you stretch it out in whatever way you
like but in a consistent way across
37:46
all the images you figure out a way to serialize
in which way you want to read
37:49
off the pics also used to call him
37:55
ok ok so let's say we have a for pixel grayscale
image which is the terrible
38:05
example you might think it i dont wanna confuse
people especially because
38:09
someone pointed out to me later after I made
this figure that red green and blue
38:12
are two color channels but here to red green
and blue course on the closest
38:15
this is a complete screw-up on my part so
I apologize not color channels just
38:21
three different colored closest sorry about
that okay
38:33
large exactly how do we make this all be a
single sized a column vector
38:47
the answer is you always always resize images
to be basically the same size we
38:52
can't easily deal with different size than
just a weekend we might go into
38:56
that later but the simplest thing to think
of it as just resize every single
38:59
image to exact same size as the simplest thing
because we want to ensure that all
39:04
of them are kind of comparable of the same
stuff so that we can make these
39:08
columns and we can analyze the school patterns
that are aligned in the space
39:12
in fact state of the art collectors the way
they actually work on this is the
39:18
only one square images so if you have a very
long and these methods will
39:21
actually work worse because many of them what
they do is to squash it that's what
39:25
we do still works fairly well so I feel very
long like panorama just tried to
39:30
put that somewhere like some online service
chances are my work worse
39:34
because they'll probably want to put it through
come that they will make it a
39:36
square because these comments always work
on squares you can make them work
39:41
on anything but that's just practice what
happens usually any other questions
39:45
are
interpreting the W the pacifier yeah yeah
so each image get through this
39:58
anyone else would like to interpret this or
so another way to actually put it one
40:04
way that I didn't hear but it's also a nice
way of looking at it is that
40:07
basically every single score is just a weighted
sum of all the pixel values and
40:12
the image and these rates are we get to choose
those eventually but I just a
40:16
giant weighted sum it's really all it's doing
is it's coming up colors right
40:20
it's coming up colors at different spatial
positions so one way to one way
40:25
that was brought up in terms of how we can
interpret this w classified concrete
40:29
is that it's kind of like a bit like a template
matching thing so here's what
40:33
I've done is I trained classifier and I have
a show you how to do that yet but I
40:37
trained my weight matrix and then come back
to the second I'm taking out every
40:41
single one of those rows that we've learned
every single classifier and I'm
40:45
reshaping in back to an end
40:46
so that I can visualize it so I'm taking it
originally just a giant blow-up 3072
40:51
numbers I we ship it back to the image to
undo the distortion have done and
40:55
then I have all these templates and so for
example what you see here is that
40:59
plane it's like a blue blob here the reason
you see blue blob is that if you
41:04
looked at the color channels of this plane
template you'll see that in the
41:08
blue channel you have lots of positive weights
because those positive weights
41:11
if they see me values then they interact with
those and they get a little
41:15
contribution to the score so this plane classifiers
really just counting up the
41:19
amount of blue stuff in the image across all
these special occasions and if you
41:23
look at the red and green channel for the
plane classifier you might find a
41:26
zero values or even negative values right
that's the plan classifier
41:30
price for all these other images to say a
frog you can almost see the template
41:35
of Prague their right to it looking for some
green starfish green stuff has
41:38
positive weights in here and then we see some
brown starfish things on the side
41:42
so if that gets butt over an image and dot
product it will get a high score one
41:49
thing to note here is a look at this
41:51
the car classifier that's not a very like
nice template of a car also hear
41:56
the horse looks a bit weird what's up that
was the car looking wherein lies
42:01
the horse looking weird yeah yeah basically
that's what's going in the
42:11
data the horses someone facing left somewhere
right and this classifier
42:14
really is not very powerful classifier and
has to combine the two modes it has
42:19
to do both things at the same time staying
up with us two headed horse in
42:22
there and you can in fact say that just when
this result there's probably more
42:25
left facing horses in seaport in the right
because the stronger they're also
42:30
for car right we can have a car like 45 degrees
to the left or right or front
42:35
and this classifier here is the optimal way
of mixing across like merging all
42:40
those modes into a single template because
that's where forcing it to do
42:43
what we're actually doing that's and neural
networks they don't have this
42:46
downside they can actually have in principle
they can have a template for
42:50
this car that card upcoming combined across
them for giving them more power
42:53
to actually carry out this classification
more properly but for now
42:56
we are constrained by this
42:57
question
43:08
yes something so a train time we would not
be taken just exactly what will be
43:18
generating them stretching them stealing them
and we'll be putting all that
43:21
that's going to become a huge part of getting
to work very well so yes I will
43:25
be doing a huge amount of that stuff for everything
will change that we're going
43:30
to elucidate many other training examples
of ships since rotates and
43:33
stews and that works much better
how these templates chain taking the average
43:47
person so you want to explicitly set a template
and the way your set the
43:56
template is your average across all the images
and that becomes your template
44:01
yeah
so this classifier it binds they would do
something similar I would guess
44:13
it would work worse because the classifier
when you look at its Michael
44:18
formerly what it optimizes for it I don't
think he would have a minimum of
44:22
what you described in just a min of the images
but that would be like intuitive
44:26
Lee decent heuristic to perhaps that awaits
in the initialization or split
44:30
something related to it
44:34
yeah yeah but we might be going to that I'll
be able to return to their several
44:40
several things
44:43
different colors red which is saying that
there's probably more red cars in
45:06
the dataset and it may not work for you in
fact yellow cards might be for this
45:11
time so this thing just does not have capacity
to do all of that which is why
45:16
the powerful enough it can capture all these
different modes correctly and so
45:19
this will just go after the numbers there's
more red cars that's where it
45:23
will go if this was grayscale I'm not sure
if that would work better he'll
45:28
come back to that actually
you might expect as I mentioned for imbalanced
45:40
datasets what you might expect
45:42
not exactly what you might expect lots of
cats is that the cat bias would be
45:49
higher because this class this classifier
is just used to large numbers
45:53
based on the loss but we have to go into loss
function to exactly see how that
45:57
will play out so it's hard to say right now
46:01
another interpretation of the classifier that
also someone else pointed out that
46:05
I'd like to point out is you can think of
these images as very high-dimensional
46:09
points in a 3072 dimensional space right into
3072 pixels space space every image
46:17
is a point and these linear classifiers are
describing these gradients across
46:22
the three thousand something two dimensional
space these scores are this
46:25
region and negative to positive along some
liquor direction across the space
46:28
and so for example here for a classifier I'm
taking the first row of W which is
46:33
the car class and to the line here is indicating
the zero level set of the
46:37
classifier in other words that long that line
the car classifier has a zero score
46:42
so the car classifier there has 20 and then
their arrows indicating the
46:46
direction along which it will color the space
with more and more
46:51
harness score similar we have three different
classifiers in this example
46:56
they will also respond to these gradients
with particular level set and
46:59
they're basically trying to go in if all these
punks they are in the space and
47:05
these local suppliers we initialize then randomly
saw this car classifier would
47:08
have its level set at random and then you'll
see when we actually do the
47:11
optimization as we optimize this will start
your shift turn animal protein
47:16
isolate the car class and will like through
fun to watch these classifiers
47:20
trained because it will rotate will snap into
the car crossing Dr Jekyll and will
47:25
try to like separate out all the cars from
all the upholding of course it's
47:28
really amusing to watch so that's another
way of interpreting that ok
47:33
here's a question for you given all these
interpretations would be a very
47:37
hard to such a pacifier works what would you
expect to work really really not
47:43
well with a linear classifier
47:51
concurrent circle see our closest are your
classes exactly how I see so you're
48:05
in search of describing is in this interpretation
of space in your images
48:10
in one class would be in a blob and then your
other classes like around it so I'm
48:15
not sure exactly what that would look like
if you actually space but yes
48:19
you're right in that case clinic awesome I
will not be able to separate out those
48:22
but what about in terms of like what would
the images look like you would
48:26
look at the studio setup images clearly say
that later classifier will probably
48:31
not do very well
here ya got
49:02
trained classifier and that I do a negative
of it negative image of that
49:39
classifier you still see the edges and you'll
say okay that's an airplane
49:42
obviously by the shape battalion classifier
all the colors would be
49:45
exactly wrong and so the cost I would hate
that airplane
49:49
example
50:02
dogs dogs dogs and one closest dogs in on
the right and you think that would be
50:12
a problem right
50:27
white background or something that would be
a problem it wouldn't be a problem I
50:32
wouldn't be a problem
50:37
transformation
50:52
you're saying that may be more difficult thing
would be if your dog that our work
50:56
in some ways according to class why wouldn't
it be a problem if you actually
51:00
do something in the center and something on
the right doesn't actually have an
51:04
understanding up especially on that actually
find right there would be a
51:08
relatively easy because you would have positive
weights in the middle
51:15
ok
51:25
yes so this is really really what it's doing
here really what this is doing is
51:34
it's counting up coming up colors and special
positions anything that messes
51:38
with this will be really hard actually to
go back to your point if you had a
51:41
grayscale data set by the way that would work
51:44
not very well with our customers will probably
not work if you could see far
51:48
10 and you made or grayscale then doing the
exact same classification grayscale
51:53
images would probably work really terribly
because you can't pick up on
51:56
the colors you have to pick up on these textures
and fine details now and you
52:00
just can't localize them because they could
be very positions can't
52:03
consistently come to cross it would be kind
of a disaster
52:08
another example would be different textures
if you have say all of your
52:11
text are blue but these texts could be different
types then this doesn't really
52:16
like say these two different types but they
can be spatially invariant
52:20
that would be terrible terrible get so just
remind you I think nearly there
52:29
would find this function so with specific
case and W we're looking at
52:35
some test images we're getting some scores
out and just looking forward
52:38
we're headed now is with some setting up w
for getting some scores for all these
52:43
images and so for example with this setting
up w in this image we're seeing
52:47
that the cat score is 2.9 but there are some
classes I've got a higher score
52:51
like dog so that's not very good right but
some classes have negative scores
52:54
which is good for this image so this is kind
of a medium result for this waits
52:59
for this image in here we see that the car
class just correct for their has the
53:04
highest score which is going to write so visiting
W work too well on this image
53:08
here we see that the class is a very low score
so terribly on that so we're
53:14
headed now is we're going to define what we
call a loss function and this loss
53:19
function will quantify this intuition of what
we considered good or bad right now
53:23
we're just eyeballing these numbers are saying
what's good what's
53:26
which actually write down the mathematical
expression that tells us
53:29
exactly like these setting up w across our
test is 12.5 bad or 1220 whatever
53:35
bad or 110 bad because then once we have a
defined specifically we're going to be
53:40
looking forw that minimize the loss and it
will be set up in such a way that
53:44
when you have a loss of very low numbers like
say even zero and then your
53:48
correctly classifying all your images but
if you have a very high loss then
53:53
everything is messed up in W is not good at
all so we're going to find a lot of
53:56
action and then look for different w's that
actually do very well across all of
54:01
it so that's roughly what's coming up
54:03
well-defined loss function which is a quantify
a way to quantify how bad HW is
54:09
on our dataset the loss function as a function
of your entire training set and
54:13
your rates we don't have control over the
transfer of control of weeds then
54:19
we're going to look at the process of optimization
how to efficiently find the
54:22
set of weights w that works across all of
the images and gives us a very low
54:27
loss and then eventually what we'll do is
we'll go back and look at this
54:30
expression classifier that we saw we're going
to start meddling with the
54:34
function here so we're going to expend effort
to not be that simple your
54:38
expression but we're going to make it slightly
more complex will get a workout
54:41
and then we can slightly more complex and
will get a coalition that work out
54:44
but otherwise the entire framework will stay
unchanged all the time will be
54:48
competing these course dysfunctional formal
be changing but we're going to
54:52
some sort of course through some function
and will make it more elaborate
54:56
overtime and then we're identifying some loss
function and we're looking at what
55:01
waits what primaries are given a very low
loss and that's a setup will be
55:04
working with going forward so next class will
look into loss functions and then
55:09
we'll go to Arsenal Emirates income that's
so I guess this is my last light
55:13
so I can take up any last questions and
55:23
sorry sorry sorry I didn't hear
55:36
the project optimization are sometimes in
opposition settings you can operate
55:41
these innovative approaches are basically
the way this will work we'll
55:45
see we'll always start off with the random
W so that will give us some loss
55:49
and then we we don't have a process of finding
right away the best set of
55:53
weights but we do have a process for is iteratively
slightly improving the
55:57
weights so little see as we look at the loss
function and will find a gradient
56:01
and space and will march down so what we do
know how to do is how do we slightly
56:06
improved a set of weights we don't know how
to do the problem of just buying the
56:09
best way through right away we don't know
how to do that because especially
56:12
when these functions are very complex likes
a intercom that's a huge landscape
56:17
of its just a very intractable problem is
that your question I'm not sure
how
56:31
do we deal with the color problem
so ok so so here we saw that the linear
56:40
classifier for car was this red template for
a car and neural network basically
56:44
what we'll do is we'll meet will you can look
at it as stacking when you're
56:47
classifier to some degree so what it will
end up doing is it will have all
56:50
these little templates really for rent cars
cars cars cars going this way or
56:55
that way or that way there will be assigned
to the technique every one of
56:58
these different modes and then they will be
combined across them on the second
57:01
layer so basically you have these are looking
for different types of course
57:04
and then next year on will be just like ok
I just take a way to tell if you guys
57:08
are doing or operation over you and then we
can detect cars in all of their modes
57:13
of their positions that makes sense that's
roughly homework